# POOJA NAYAR

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST - UX**

Contact No: +91 9004214094

Email Id: pooja.mahamuni205@gmail.com



#### **PROFILE:**

More than 6 years' experience in IT working in the following areas: Requirements Gathering, Prototyping, Tests, Development and Leadership.

Experience in Gathering / Analysing and Specifying Requirements, Direct Communication with Customers / Developers and Business Areas, Elaboration of Proposals / Use Cases / Functional and Non-Functional Requirements Document, Manuals, UML Diagrams, Scope Control, Requirements Prioritization by Business Value, Product Backlog Management, Prototype Development Focused on Usability.

Experience as **Product Owner** using Agile Methodology (SCRUM). Knowledge about User Stories.

#### **PERSONAL QUALITIES:**

- Possess strong conceptual skills and the ability to carry ideas from planning stages to implementation
- High energy, motivated, passion for design technologies for the web
- Known to challenge traditional methods for more innovative and creative approaches
- Process-oriented, big picture person with an eye for details
- Equal strengths both technically & creatively

### **ROLES & EXPERTISE:**

#### **Project Manager / Team Lead**

- Manage timelines, team priorities, and schedules
- Coordinate with clients regarding scope changes and change orders
- Coordinate with team members to meet scheduled deadlines

## **Information Architect**

- Site architectures, structures and navigational systems
- Ability to help clients come to grips with overwhelming amounts of information that needs to be logically organized
- Site documentation

#### **UX Research**

- Correlate concrete features and functionality with business needs.
- Communicate solutions to complex problems both visually and verbally.
- Work with clients to co-create an ideal experience for their target users.
- Understand layout, typography and visual hierarchy.
- Document design decisions and functionality for developers.
- Work with developers to implement event tracking.
- Find answers to usability questions in analytics and other data.
- Work with the design team to brainstorm improvements.

Address: 204, Bhaveshwar Heights, Plot No. – 87, Sector – 06, Karanjade, New Panvel – 410206,

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Company : M/S ILM INNOVATIVE SOLUTIONS PVT LTD

Designation : UX LEAD

**Duration**: 24th August 2012 – 22<sup>nd</sup> September 2018

**Location** : Mumbai

Sr. No	Duration	Project Name	Role	Client Location	Responsibility
1	July 2018 - Ongoing	Assam Tourism – Website and Mobile App to Explore the Tourism in Assam	Requirement Analyst	Assam	Responsible for Requirement Gathering and Analysis and Co- ordinating with the UX, UI and Design Team to achieve the goals
2	Sep 2017 - Ongoing	Hum life Ecommerce – An Organic Products ecommerce website and mobile app to promote Women Empowerment through employment	Product Owner	Internal Product	Gather and document requirements and business rules (diagrams creation, prototype, and use cases) defects and improvements reporting and Conduct Demos to Higher Management
3	July 2017 – Feb 2018	Exclusave Card – Claim Discounts & Offers through Mobile App in Saudi	Project Owner	Saudi Arabia	Gather and document requirements and business rules, scope control, execution, defects and improvements reporting. Was responsible to conduct regular demos and brainstorming sessions with the Client
4	May 2017 - June 2017	Board Book - Board Books is Board Meeting software, which can efficiently manage your Board Meetings through a system driven technology	UX & Requirement Analyst	Mumbai	Responsible for Requirement Gathering and Analysis and Co- ordinating with the UX and Design Team to achieve the goals
5	Jan 2017 - April 2017	Bahrain Exhibitions Centre's - Job Card – Issue Management System	Requirement Analyst	Bahrain	Responsible for Requirement Gathering, Client and Team Co- ordination, UX Research, Features finalization, Wire framing, App Flow Design Review & Conduct Demos
6	June 2016 – Dec 2016	Yalabee – End to End Restaurant Management solution	UX & Requirement Analyst	Internal Product	Responsible for End to End Product brainstorming and Planning. Including Market Research and UX Analysis. Co-ordinated with cross functional teams to achieve the requirements.  Technologies: Balsamiq Mock-ups, Adobe Illustrator
7	Dec 2015- May 2016	Jio mField - Jio mField is an application used for processing work orders related to O&M assets. The application allows evidence based maintenance, fault location on maps, reserve & return material, access to equipment history, notification update and order closure.	UX & Requirement Analyst	Mumbai	Responsible for End to End Product brainstorming and Planning. Including Research and UX Analysis. Co-ordinated with cross functional teams to achieve the requirements. Was responsible to conduct regular demos and brainstorming sessions with SME's to achieve the desired flow.

Address: 204, Bhaveshwar Heights, Plot No. – 87, Sector – 06, Karanjade, New Panvel – 410206,

8	Sep 2015 – Nov 2015	<b>Jio Now</b> – Android App used by Jio Employees to Track and resolve On site Issues.	UX & Requirement Analyst	Mumbai	Responsible for Requirement Gathering and Analysis and Co- ordinating with the UX and Design Team to achieve the goals Technologies: Invision
9	Feb 2015 - Aug 2015	IMMAP Royal – Saudi's Royal Family Genealogy Records in a Tree View	Project Owner	Bahrain	Responsible for Requirement Gathering, Client Co-ordination, UX Research, Features finalization, Wire framing, App Flow Design Review and Development of the Project. Conducted demo to explain the application flow to the end user. Technologies: Groovy on Grails, MS Project
10	July 2014 - Jan 2015	IlmTube – User Friendly Islamic App to provide authenticated content in the form of Videos and Audios.	UX + Product Owner	Internal Product	Responsible for UX Research, Features finalization, Wire framing, App Flow Design Review and Development of Admin Panel. Guiding Team for Mobile App Development Flow. Technologies: Groovy on Grails, Amazon Aws, H2 DB, Neo4j Graph database, Android Eclipse
11	Mar 2013 - June 2014	K-lander - School Management System	Backend Developer	Internal Product	Responsible for Planning use cases, Conduct Demos and implementation of Database architecture planning and Development of School hierarchy management, Attendance and Media & Documents Management Modules.  Technologies: Groovy on Grails, Amazon Aws, MySQL
12	Nov 2012 - Feb 2013	Online Doctor's Portal	Junior Backend Developer	USA	Responsible for planning and implementation of Media and Website Builder Module Technologies: Groovy on Grails, Amazon Aws, Dynamo Db
13	Aug 2012 - Oct 2012	-	Trainee	-	Training Programme

Technical Knowledge					
Software:	Office (Word, Excel, Power Point, Access, Outlook, Visio, Project),				
Databases:	Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, Mongo, Neo4j, Dynamo DB				
Prototyping tools:	Balsamiq Mock-ups, Adobe Illustrator, In Vision				
Programming Languages:	Visual Basic, C++, C, Java, Groovy on Grails				

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS:							
BSc in Information Technology	:	Mumbai Ur	niversity, March 2011				
HSC	:	Pune University, February 2008					
SSC :		Pune University, March 2006					
Additional courses :		Diploma In .NET Framework From NIIT					
PERSONAL DETAILS:							
Marital Status		:	Married				
Date of Birth		:	20th May 1991				
Nationality		:	Indian				
Passport No.		:	P3100761				
Hobbies		:	Listening Music, Surfing, Cooking, Reading				
Languages Known		:	English, Hindi, Marathi				
References		:	Available on request				
I confirm that the information provided by me is true to the best of my knowledge and							
belief.							
Place:							

Date:

POOJA NAYAR